Contact

udayakrishna@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/udayakrishna-bandaru (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Reference Data
Data Modeling
Business Analysis

Certifications

Oracle8i: Database Administration Amazon Web Services Big Data Specialty

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Udayakrishna Bandaru

Vice President - Data Science & Engineering at Lynk Global Hyderabad

Summary

Senior leader with experience managing technology for multiple business divisions for global companies. Implemented technology for managing company wide data. Well versed with business domains Ratings/Risk, Fixed Income, Structured Finance, Municipals, Corporate, Company/Market data, Identifiers and other relevant financial products. Established talent/delivery centres from ground up to support global expansion and delivery.

Experience

Lynk Global Vice President - Data Science & Engineering October 2019 - Present (11 months) Hyderabad Area, India

At LYNK we are connecting the worlds greatest minds. We connect world class experts with clients across the globe for everything from consultations to due diligence reports, to onsite engagements and corporate training. Global top tier customers such as consulting firms, private equity funds, venture capital, hedge funds, asset management firms, governments, corporates and even startups have chosen to work with Lynk.

Lynk was founded with a mission to democratize access to knowledge, challenging the 'traditional' expert network business model, by leveraging proprietary technology and our high calibre team from a diverse range of backgrounds. Get in touch or find out more at https://lynk.global

S&P Global Functional Lead October 2017 - October 2019 (2 years 1 month) Hyderabad, India

Responsible for managing staff/delivery for mission critical fundamental products in Ratings Data Technology from Hyderabad, India. Managing talent acquisition, talent development along with transformation to Agile and introducing Lean practices. Enhancing data pipeline(s) to feed new data sets

Page 1 of 3

to applications using Lamda architecture (speed/batch layers). Working on building powerful and flexible data lake in cloud to provide critical data for business analytics/data science projects.

S&P Capital IQ Senior Director, Software Engineering November 2012 - January 2016 (3 years 3 months) Hyderabad, India

Tasked with setting up development center, formed/hired multiple teams to support global expansion targets. Managed teams for on time delivery and global collaboration. Mentored and Coached team for performance, career growth, stability and continuous learning. Worked with local vendors to hire and manage talent. Responsible for program delivery from Hyderabad.

Citi Senior Data Architect May 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 6 months)

New York, New York

As performance specialist, was responsible for tuning multiple applications, BI reports etc. Created data models for internal projects and upgrades. Partnered with DBA group to implement workload management, session and access management.

Standard & Poor's
Senior Director, Ratings Data Services
January 1998 - May 2012 (14 years 5 months)
New York, New York

Joined as developer for business critical web based application. Performed all phases of SDLC in this complex business critical project, moved on as Tech/ Team lead managing not just this one project but other related and revenue generating applications. Expanded roles and responsibilities to manage multiple highly complex and business critical databases and other critical applications. Created golden copy of all domain data by integrating multiple databases. Managed Change, data governance, venrdors along the way. Interfaced with business users to set the development strategy/direction for business critical product(s).

Kintetsu World Express (U.S.A.), Inc. Database Administrator March 1998 - 1998 (less than a year) Jericho, New York Managed and supported multiple databases in production and development areas. Performed data modeling, performance tuning, code re-architecture, production backups etc. Created/Restored QA databases using export/import tools.

CRI India Ltd Systems Engineer 1994 - 1998 (4 years)

Chennai, India

Started as tester to learn the application and moved onto development in Oracle. Developed multiple modules in Oracle and Oracle Forms for managing maintenance/service documents. Lead a small team to design and develop DocTrac a tracking application for Singapore Airlines and Manila Airlines.

Singapore Airlines Systems Engineer 1995 - 1997 (2 years) North West, Singapore

Implemented technology/systems for Engine Overhaul Division Singapore Airlines. Deployed DocTrac system in Singapore Airlines and further customized this application for Engine Overhaul Division.

Education

Sri Venkateswara University, Tirupati, Andhra Pradesh, India Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.), Computer Applications · (1991 - 1994)

Govt. Degree College, Nagari, Andhra Pradesh, India Bachelor's Degree, Mathis, Physics, Chemsitry (1988 - 1991)